http://www.pbrnow.com/about/privacy-policy/

CORONAVIRUS/COVID-19: Learn more about the PBR's response to the pandemic.
Next
Effective Date: [12/31/19]
What’s New?
We’ve added more detail in what data we collect, how we use your data, and who we share it with.
We’ve updated our policy to include new rights to opt out of the sale of your data under applicable laws.
We’ve included additional information about rights of some customers under new California laws relating to data privacy.
PBR PRIVACY POLICY
PBR knows that our customers are a key part of what makes the PBR community successful. Our commitment to our customers includes handling your data responsibly.
This Privacy Policy describes how we use the data (which may include your personal information) we collect from you through our websites (“Site”), when you buy a ticket or other merchandise from us online, when you view PBR and/or other sports programming on one of our online channels, including RidePass.com, and when you attend our events in person (collectively our “Services”).
Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand how we will treat your information.
WHO WE ARE
HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU
INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT
DISCLOSURES OF YOUR INFORMATION
MARKETING AND ADVERTISING
SOCIAL SHARING FEATURES
COOKIES
DO NOT TRACK
WHO WE ARE
We are Professional Bull Riders, LLC and affiliated entities including RidePass.com and American Bucking Bull, Inc. We are also part of Endeavor and its affiliated companies (“Endeavor”). If you would like a list of relevant entities, please email us at dataprivacy@img.com.
Like any company, we use a variety of third party businesses and partners to market and provide our Services to you. Some of those companies are part of Endeavor and some are third parties that we partner with or support our operations so we can provide the best experience to you.
HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU
Directly From You
You may provide us with personal information in a number of ways, such as when you:
Provide information to us via our websites, applications, and other digital channels by signing up, creating accounts (including using social media login), filling out forms, commenting, or otherwise engaging with our online services;
Communicate with us by e-mail or phone;
Subscribe to e-mails and/or newsletters;
Report a problem or request support for any of our Services;
Buying a ticket or merchandise from us online at PBR.com, PBRShop.com, RidePass or one of our partners
Interact with our Social Media accounts;
Participate in our contests, promotions, sweepstakes or surveys;
Subscribing to and watching PBR and other content online at RidePass, PBR and/or RidePass YouTube channels, and other online official video or streaming partners; and
Attending any PBR owned, sanctioned or co-promoted event.
Information We Collect From Other Sources
We work closely with third parties (for example, technical service providers, ticketing providers, promotions companies, advertising networks, analytics providers, and search information providers) and may receive information about you from them. Depending on the relationship and activity, they will provide us with certain information that will help us understand how you interact with PBR Services so we can tailor our marketing and provide better, more personalized Services to you. In some cases, third parties also provide us with information that helps us keep track of transactions, address technical or logistical issues, prevent fraud, or keep our PBR community safe from security threats.
We may also receive and display information and content which you make publically available on your social media account when you use social media logins for our Services or interact with any of our content (such as contests).
Some of our key partners and service providers who may provide us with personal information about you are:
Media and digital content partners, who we partner with to share exclusive content, including PPV packages of PBR events;
E-commerce platforms and service, which provide PBR merchandise to PBR fans around the world;
Ticket sellers around the world who sell tickets to PBR events; and
Venues which host PBR events and provide various marketing, advertising, customer support, and security services related to PBR events.
We may also receive and display information and content which you make publically available on your social media account, such as when you post using one of our promoted hashtags.
INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT
Categories of personal information collected
Categories of sources from which personal information is collected
Business or commercial purposes for collection, use, and sharing
Categories of third parties with whom some or all of the personal may be shared
Personal and online identifiers (such as first and last name, email address, phone number, usernames, or unique online identifiers)
Directly from you
Marketing partners
To provide and Improve the Services
Personalization of the Services
Customer support
Marketing and targeted advertising
Security and fraud prevention
Customer service partners
Marketing sponsors and partners
Ad networks
E-Commerce vendors
Endeavor
Analytics services
Financial Account Information (such as credit card numbers, bank account information, Paypal account information)
Directly from you
Payment providers
E-Commerce vendors
To provide the Services
To sell you merchandise, tickets, or PBR content
E-Commerce vendors
Payment providers
Fraud and cybersecurity companies
Endeavor
Customer Profile Information (such as race, gender, age range, income range, ad demographics)
Directly from you
Marketing partners
Advertising networks
Third party data providers
To provide and improve the Services
Personalization of the Services
Direct marketing
Targeted advertising
E-Commerce Vendors
Communications with you (such as customer support messages, emails, social media posts)
Directly from You
Customer support partners
To Provide and Improve the Services
Customer Support
Endeavor
Analytics services
Technology service Providers
E-Commerce vendors
Customer Service Partners
Online Activity Information (such as browsing history, search history, interactions with a website, email, application, or advertisement)
Directly from You
Cookies and similar technologies
Marketing partners
Advertising networks
Third party data providers
To Provide and Improve the Services
Personalization of the Services
Direct marketing
Targeted advertising
Endeavor
Technology service providers
Analytics services
Ad networks
Non-Precise Geolocation information (such as zip or area code, state, country)
Directly from you
Cookies and similar technologies
Marketing sponsors
Technology service providers
Ad networks
To provide and improve the Services to you
Personalization of the Services
Fraud and cybersecurity
Direct marketing
Targeted advertising
Endeavor
Ad networks
Technology service providers
Marketing sponsors
Sensory information (such as audio, electronic, visual, or similar information)
Directly from you (such as when you interact with certain apps at our events)
Technology service providers (such as apps and third party analytics platforms activating services at our events)
To provide and improve the Services
Personalization of the services
Enhancing live event experiences
Research and development
Endeavor
Technology services providers
Inferences drawn from the above information about your predicted characteristics and preferences
Endeavor
Third party data providers
Marketing sponsors
To Provide and improve the Services
Personalization of the Services
Direct marketing
Targeted advertising
Analytics
Endeavor
Ad networks
Marketing sponsors
Technology service providers
Analytics companies
Other information about you that is linked to the personal information above
Directly from you
Endeavor
Third party data providers
Marketing sponsors.
To Provide and Improve the Services
Personalization of the Services
Endeavor
Ad networks
Marketing sponsors
We may also use the information we have about you
as necessary if we believe there has been a breach of the Terms of Use or the rights of any third party, or
to comply with legal and regulatory requirements.
We combine information we receive from other sources with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We use this combined information for the purposes set out above.
DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION
We do share data with third parties, including event sponsors and Endeavor, and the other categories of partners as listed above. Some of these disclosures of data may be constitute a sale of data under some data privacy laws. Accordingly, we offer the option for you to opt out of the sale of your personal information, as further set forth below.
We may share your personal information with Endeavor and with selected third parties including:
business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you in order to provide you with a product or service;
business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors to provide you with information about promotions and offers;
advertisers, advertising networks and social networks that require the data to select and serve relevant advertisements to you and, in some cases, to others. For more information on how we use personal information for targeted advertising, see below; and
analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimization of the Service.
We may disclose your personal information to third parties:
If we enter into negotiations to buy, sell, or merge with any business or assets, or if we enter into bankruptcy, reorganization, or receivership, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective or eventual seller or buyer of such business or assets;
if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in the event of an emergency, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use and other agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of PBR, Endeavor, our customers, clients or others; and
to any other third party not covered in this policy with your prior consent.
MARKETING AND ADVERTISING
Targeted Advertising
We use your personal information to tailor our marketing and advertising efforts. To do this, we provide your information to third party advertising networks (such as Google Doubleclick) and social media companies (such as Facebook). When we provide data to agencies, ad networks, and other parties for targeted advertising, we do not provide them with your name, financial information, or any sensitive information (such as an government ID or date of birth, if we have collected that). We use online identifiers such as email, cookie addresses, and device identifiers to help us provide targeted advertising to you and others like you. We may also use aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. We may make use of the personal information we have collected from you to enable us to display advertisements to target audiences;
To opt out of targeted advertising, you may use the following links provided by third parties that manage opt outs for some ad networks:
http://preferences-mgr.truste.com,http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp,http://www.aboutads.info/,https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners
Email Marketing
We also add you to our mailing lists for email communications from PBR and our partners’, including Endeavor, when you sign up for our mailing lists, purchase a ticket or PBR merchandise, or subscribe to PBR content online. If you provide us with your email address in order to receive communications, you can opt out at any time by using the unsubscribe links at the bottom of our emails.
Mobile Notifications
With your consent, we may send promotional and non-promotional push notifications or alerts to your mobile device. You can deactivate these messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device.
SOCIAL SHARING FEATURES
You may be able to use social sharing features and other integrated tools on the Site such as the Facebook "Like" button. These features and tools may permit you to share actions you take on our Service with other media, and vice versa. Your use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the service that provides the social sharing feature Please remember, though, that use of the information you share on social media sites will be governed by the privacy policies of the social media provider, and we are not responsible for how they treat the information.
COOKIES
We and trusted third parties use cookies and similar technologies on the Site to collect and process personal information. For more information, please see our Cookie Notice.
DO NOT TRACK
Some web may transmit "do-not-track" signals to the websites with which the user communicates. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether you intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether you even are aware of them. Because there currently is no industry standard concerning what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals, we currently do not take action in response to these signals.
STORAGE AND TRANSFER OF INFORMATION
We operate the Services in and from a number of different jurisdictions, but the Site is primarily operated from the United States, which is where your information will likely be stored and processed. Your information may be disclosed in response to inquiries or requests from government authorities or to respond to legal process in the countries in which we operate and/or store your information.
CHILDREN
We do not knowingly collect information from children who are under 13 years old. If you are a parent or guardian of a child who is 13-16 years old and using our Services, please send us an email at dataprivacy@PBR.com to opt in or request deletion of any personal information we may have collected about the child. If you are a parent or guardian of a child who is under 13 years old and using our Services, please contact us to arrange for deletion of any personal information we may have collected about the child.
OPTING OUT OF THE SALE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
WE DO NOT SELL YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR MONEY.
However, sometimes we share your data with sponsors, vendors, Endeavor, and third party advertising networks. These transfers, which are used to provide you with certain Services and/or to more effectively provide you with personalized Services (including advertising), can be deemed a sale under some data privacy laws.
You may opt out of the sale of your personal information by clicking on the Do Not Sell My Personal Information button on our site or calling 1-866-983-0571. You will be asked to provide certain information to us in order to exercise this option so we can verify your identity and locate your records with us.
Please note that your decision to opt out of the sale of your personal information may impact the availability and quality of some of the Services provided to you. For example, if you choose to opt out of the sale of your personal information with regard to PBR RidePass, your account will need to be suspended because the service relies on certain data to function.
YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
California residents have certain rights with respect to the personal information collected by businesses. If you are a California resident, you may exercise the following rights regarding your personal information, subject to our ability to verify your request and certain other limitations:
Information about You: You may ask for us to state what categories of personal information about you we have, and the categories of sources from which we collect your personal information;
Receive a Copy of Your Data: You may request the categories and specific pieces of information (if any) we have about you, the categories of personal information that we have disclosed about you for a business purpose, and the categories of third parties with which we have shared personal information in the previous 12 months.
Delete Your Data: You may request that we delete the personal information we have collected from you.
Do-Not-Sell: You may opt out of our sale(s) of your personal information, as “sale” is defined by California law. Please see above for more information.
Non-Discrimination: California law prohibits discrimination against you for exercising your privacy rights.
Note: Where certain technologies rely on your data to provide the Services, the absence of that data may impact the operation of the Services.
How to Exercise Your Rights. To exercise any of the above rights, please follow the instructions below:
By phone at 1-866-983-0571
Online by using this webform
If you have an online account with PBR RidePass, you may also exercise your rights through the menu options available to you in the account settings.
If you have any other request you wish to submit to the PBR Privacy Team, you may submit a general information request dataprivacy@PBR.com.
Verification Process and Required Information. All requests must be verified. Some requests, including receiving a copy of your data or requests made by an agent claiming to be acting on your behalf, are subject to heightened requirements. If we cannot verify your identity based on the information provided, a request for a copy of your data shall be treated as a request for information and if we cannot verify your identity, a request to delete personal information may be treated as a request to opt-out of the sale of personal information.
Authorized Agent. You may designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf. An Authorized Agent must have written documentation of their authority to act on your behalf, such as a Power of Attorney.
SECURITY
We use a variety of administrative, physical, and technology solutions, including engaging with qualified cybersecurity companies, to protect your information from unauthorized access, loss, or misuse. Because there is always some risk in transmitting information over the internet and otherwise processing information, we cannot and do not guarantee or warrant the security of any information that you transmit on or through the Services or that we otherwise maintain.
LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES
Our Services, newsletters, email updates and other communications may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of others, including our partner networks, retail partners, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.
UPDATES
Any updates we may make to our Privacy Policy will be posted on this page, and we may also provide a website notice of any material changes for a reasonable period of time. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree or consent to these updates or changes, do not continue to use the Services.
CONTACT
Questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy should be emailed to dataprivacy@PBR.com.
